Elizabeth! Hey!
エリザベス　おい
Elizabeth!
エリザベス
Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
真っ白な景色にいま誘われて
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
僕は行くよ　まだ見ぬ世界へ
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
迷子のまま旅していた
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
鼠色の空の下
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
日替わりの地図 いくつもの夢が滲んでいた
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
いつかはさ
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
ちっぽけな僕のこの歩幅でも
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
あの雲の向こうまで行けるかな
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
強がって
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
キズついた
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
心透かしたように
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
降り出した
Furidashita
And the raindrops
雨粒たちが
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
乱反射繰り返す
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
真っ直ぐな光が
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
交差して
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
行き先も告げぬまま
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
どこまでも
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
突き抜ける
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
淡い残像　両目に焼きつけて
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
この空の下
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
どんなとこにいても
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
届くはずなんだ
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
まだ見ぬ世界へ
Mada minu sekai e
I'm not supposed to tell anyone this, but according to Barry,
んで　これは内緒なんだけど
バリーの話じゃ
the Colonel is trying to expose the people in the military involved in that Lab 5 place.
大佐は第五なんとかってとこに関係した軍の連中を
あぶり出そうとしてるんだってさ
Research Laboratory 5...
第五研究所
Al...
アル
I have to go.
行かなきゃ
ヒューズさんを殺したヤツのことが分かるかもしれない
I might find out something about
the person who killed Mr. Hughes.
えっ　ちょっと待ってよ
Hey, hang on! What about the secret to your body?
体の秘密は
帰って来たら教えてあげる
I'll tell you when I get back.
ええっ　そんな
What's up with that?!
Well, I'm off.
行ってくるね
Make sure you come back.
ちゃんと　帰って来てね
うん　約束する
Yes. I promise.
Done already?
もう　終わり
Can I eat you now?
食べていい
Shut up, you're in the way!
うるさい　邪魔
Lieutenant!
中尉
Out of bullets? Out of bullets?
弾切れ　弾切れ
Then it's time for dinner!
それじゃあいただきます
Looks like I made it in time.
間に合ったか
Colonel...
大佐
Why did you come?!
なんで出てきたんですか
Despite whatever may have happened to us, if you had just ignored it, you could have escaped suspicion!
私たちに何かあっても
無視していれば敵の追及を逃れられるのに
And yet, you came out here?!
こんな所にのこのこと
Seriously, are you an idiot?!
あなたは本当にバカですか
Okay, okay. I'm an idiot.
ああ　分かった分かった　私がバカだった
What the hell was that guy...
何なんだよあいつは
Colonel! Our target is on the run!
大佐　目標が移動を開始
Sergeant, pull out!
曹長　撤収だ
Don't leave a trace!
ゴミ１つ残すな
Hayate, you stay with the Sergeant!
ハヤテ号は曹長と一緒にいなさい
Yes, sir!
はい
Colonel.
大佐
What is it?
なんだ
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
Save it for later. We're in the middle of an operation.
あとにしろ　今は作戦行動中だ
Yes, sir.
はい
Get in!
乗れ
Yes, sir.
はい
This has something to do with Mr. Hughes, right?
ヒューズさんの件と関係があるんでしょ
Do you want to come?
来るか
Yes.
はい
Don't lose sight of him!
見失うなよ
I won't let him get away!
逃がさねぇよ
My soul keeps shaking...
魂がざわつくのさ
It's telling me where he is!
こっちだ　こっちだってなぁ
I wonder if other monsters like that fat one are going to show up?
あの太った化け物のようなヤツが
また出てくるのでしょうか
分からん　なんだったんだあれは
I don't know. What the hell was that?
I hit his vitals many times,
but it didn't seem to bother him at all.
急所に何発撃ち込んでも
平気な顔をしていました
Did he have a tattoo of Ouroboros?
もしかして　ウロボロスの入れ墨なかった
Tattoo?
入れ墨
Oh, maybe that thing...
あれがそうかしら
He had something on his tongue.
舌にあった
That's probably a homunculus.
それ　たぶん人造人間だよ
That was close, idiot!
危ねぇなバカ
Wait, wait, wait! A homunculus?!
待て待て待て　人造人間だと
There's no way something like that could exist!
そんなものはありえん
I met a homunculus by the name of Greed in the south.
南部でグリードって名前の人造人間と会った
And this is what he said.
その人言ってたよ
"There's no way there's no way."
「ありえないなんてことはありえない」って
Homunculi have extraordinary regeneration abilities.
人造人間はすごい再生能力を持ってる
Greed had half of his head blown off, but he fixed himself right away.
グリードは　頭を半分吹き飛ばされても
すぐに元どおりになっていた
But I guess that's hard to believe, huh...
って言っても　信じてはもらえないかな
We'll just have to believe you after seeing that thing.
信じるしかないわ　あんなの見せられたら
You're not going to tell me he's still alive after being burnt to a crisp and falling from the top of the tower, are you?
まさか　焼け焦げて塔の上から落ちても死なない
とか言うんじゃないだろうな
Probably.
たぶん
What is this... a nonsensical mutant all-around freak show?!
ったく
デタラメ人間の万国ビックリショーか
My body escaped into here.
オレの体はここに逃げ込んだぜ
Research Laboratory 3, huh?
軍の第三研究所か
Now we have a chance to blackmail the upper echelon.
上層部をゆするきっかけができたな
That's sufficient for this operation.
十分な収穫だ　引き揚げるぞ
We're withdrawing.
No, it's not!
十分じゃねぇよ
No! Idiot!
あっ　バカ
This is bad, Colonel.
まずいですよ大佐
No, it's actually convenient.
いや 好都合だ
What?
はあ
Outta the way!
どけ　どけ
I'm not interested in your meat!
おめぇらの肉にゃ興味はねぇんだよ
Where are you, my meat?!
どこだオレのお肉ちゃん
All personnel are to evacuate immediately!
残っている職員は速やかに退避せよ
C-Colonel!
たっ　大佐
The intruder is a vicious criminal.
侵入者は凶悪殺人犯だ
Leave his capture to us.
逮捕は我々に任せろ
The guards are to seal off all entrances!
警備兵は出入り口を封鎖
はっ
Yes, sir!
That damn Barry... which way did he go?
バリーのヤツ　どっちに行った
二手に分かれるぞ
We're splitting up.
Roger.
はい
Looks like it's been quite some time since this place was abandoned.
廃棄されてから　かなり時間がたつようだな
Could it be... an experiment room?
実験室ですかね
だとして　まともな実験ではなさそうだな
If that were true, it doesn't seem any pleasant experiments were carried out here.
Oh my, what a coincidence.
あら　偶然ね
I can't believe you stood me up.
ひどいわ　デートすっぽかして
You know, I was waiting for you.
私待ってたのよ
I wanted to see you, Jean.
会いたかったわ　ジャン
Solaris...
ソラリス　なんでここに
Why are you here?
Hey Havoc, she's got a tattoo of Ouroboros!
おい　ハボック
ウロボロスの入れ墨だぞ
オレも今知りましたよ
I just noticed that, myself!
Sorry for tricking you.
だましててごめんなさいね
Well, I can see how you were tricked.
なるほど
だまされるわけだ
You like big breasts, don't you?
お前　ボイン好きだろ
Yes! You bet I do!
大好きっす　ボイン
...I do! ...I do! ...I do!
Did you tell her anything?
この女に何かしゃべったか
I didn't tell her anything related to my work!
仕事のことは何もしゃべってませんよ
Do you know Maes Hughes?
貴様　マース·ヒューズを知っているか
He was a handsome, smart man.
頭の切れるいい男だったわね
It's a pity I couldn't finish him off-
とどめを刺せなかったのが残念だったけ
Get on your knees!
ひざまずけ　洗いざらい吐くんだ
Tell me everything you know.
That's impossible.
無理ね
You boys can't make me kneel-
あなたたちじゃ　私をひざまずかせることはでき
As expected from the hero of Ishbal.
さすがイシュヴァールの英雄
You're relentless.
容赦ないわね
H-Homunculus?!
ホ　人造人間
Oh my, looks like you did your homework, Jean.
あら　よく調べたわねジャン
As a reward, I'll show you.
ご褒美に見せてあげる
Do you see it?
見えるかしら
It's a philosopher's stone.
賢者の石よ
Humans created with this stone as their core...
この石を核につくられた人間
That's what we, homunculi, are.
それが私たち人造人間
You monsters!
化け物め
How rude.
失礼ね
We have feelings and love for our parents.
感情もある　親に対する愛情もある
We're...
私たちは
...human.
人間よ
重大な秘密を話したということは
If you're telling us your huge secret,
you must not be planning on letting us go alive.
生かして帰す気がないということか
Yes, unfortunately for you.
そう　残念だけど
Too slow!
遅い
Oh my, you can't even make your fire now.
あらあら　お得意の炎も出せないわね
What do we do now?! At this rate, we'll get tortured to death!
どうするんすか
このままじゃなぶり殺しですよ
No, it's actually convenient.
むしろ好都合だ
If there's a lot of water...
大量の水があるならば
...I just have to decompose it to create hydrogen and oxygen!
分解して水素と酸素を発生させるまで
あぁあ　ひっでぇな
Geez, just look at this thing...
I got it from my ex, too...
前の彼女からもらったやつなのに
くそっ
Damnit!
大佐　火もらえませんかねぇ
Colonel, could you give me a light?
って　無理っすね
I guess it's impossible.
私はしけたマッチか
What am I, a wet match?!
あの女　間違いなく焼けたな
That woman definitely burned up.
How can you tell?
なんで分かるんですか
においだ
By the smell.
焼死体のは何度もかいだ
I'm used to the smell of burnt corpses.
From Ishbal?
イシュヴァールの経験ですか
But we can't take her regeneration ability lightly.
だがあの再生能力は侮れん
気をつけろ
Stay alert.
Roger.
はい
ハボック
Havoc!
ハボック　しっかりしろ
Havoc, hang in there!
ダメよ
It's no use.
もう助からない
You can't save him anymore.
No!
いや
無駄よ
It's pointless!
まだまだ私は死なない
It'll take more than that to kill me!
助ける方法なら　ここにある
I can save him with this!
治療に使わせてもらう
I'm going to use it to treat him.
医療分野の錬金術は専門外だが
Medical alchemy isn't my specialty,
この石の力で底上げすれば
but if I boost my ability with this stone...
レディーの胸もとにいきなり手を突っ込むなんて
It's not very gentlemanly of you to suddenly stick your hand into a lady's chest.
紳士のすることかしら
F-Führer President!
だっ　大総統閣下
侵入者とな
An intruder?
はっ
Yes, sir! The culprit who attacked the western district jail is inside!
西区留置所を襲った犯人が中に
Colonel Mustang is after him!
マスタング大佐が 追っています
どれ　助けに行こう
I think I'll lend him a hand.
自分たちも同行します
We'll come with you, too, sir!
いや
No.
一人で十分
I'll be fine on my own.
I thought I told you.
言ったはずよ
賢者の石が核だと
The philosopher's stone is my core.
ごめんなさいね
I'm sorry.
あなたは人柱候補だけど
You're a candidate for sacrifice,
but you're going to die here.
ここで死ぬのよ
貴様
You bitch...
Why don't you die as you lay there, watching your man go cold?
目の前で　部下が冷たくなっていくのを見ながら
あなたも逝きなさい
ハボック少尉
Second Lieutenant Havoc...
Answer me... damnit...
返事をしろ　くそっ
私より　先に死ぬことは許さんぞ
I'm not going to allow you to die before me...
Havoc...
ハボック
遅かったね　姐さん
You sure took your time, lady.
見ろよ　オレの体こんなに腐っちまって
Just look how rotten my body has become.
そもそも別々の肉体と魂を一緒にしようってのが
It's impossible to place a soul on a body that doesn't belong.
無理なんだよ
他人の肉体と魂が相いれないなら
If separate souls and bodies can't be mixed,
鉄の体に人の魂の僕は
then I, who am made of a human soul and an iron body...
そうだ　僕たちが目的を果たすときまで
That's right, there's no guarantee this body will last to the time we fulfill our goal...
この体がもつ保証はないんだ
兄さん
Brother...
来たな　ラストさんよぉ
There you are, Miss Lust.
Number 66, why did you join forces with the Colonel?
ナンバー６６　なぜ大佐に協力したの
おもしろそうだからよ
Because it seemed like it'd be fun!
それにな
And also...
何よりおめぇさんを斬りてぇ
...I want to cut you up, more than anything!
困った男ね
What a troublesome man.
それに鎧君まで何　こんな所に来てしまって
And the armor boy, too? What are you doing here?
What a loss.
大損失だわ
人柱候補を　ひと晩に二人も殺さなきゃならないなんて
That I have to kill two candidates for sacrifice in one night!
人柱　二人も
Sacrifice? Two?
Yes. You and someone else.
そう　あなたともう一人
What are you blabbering on for, Miss Lust?!
ごちゃごちゃしゃべってんじゃねぇ　ラストさんよぉ
うるさい男は嫌いよ
I hate persistent guys.
さて　中尉さん
Now, Lieutenant. I'll send you to the place where I sent your superior right away.
あなたもすぐに　上司の後を追わせてあげるわね
Wait...
待って
人柱をひと晩に二人と言ったわね
You said two sacrifices in one night, right...
まさか　まさか
Don't tell me... you didn't...
き　貴様
Y...You bitch!!!
Finished?
終わり
本当に愚かで弱い　悲しい生き物ね
You humans really are foolish, weak, pitiful beings.
Lieutenant, get up and run.
中尉　立って逃げるんだ
先に逝きたいの
Do you want to die first?
そう　あなた扉を開けたの
I see... so you opened the gate.
残念だわ　人柱確定なのに
It's a shame.
Forget candidate, you're a confirmed sacrifice.
Alphonse, leave me and run.
アルフォンス君
私を置いて逃げなさい
嫌だ
No.
Run!
逃げなさい
No!
嫌だ
あなただけでも
Save yourself, at least!
嫌なんだよ
I said, no!!!
目の前で人が死んでいく
Seeing people die before my eyes...
嫌なんだ　たくさんだ
I hate it! I'm tired of it!
I'm not going to let anyone die anymore! I'll protect you!
もう誰も殺させない
守ってみせる
よく言った
Well said, Alphonse Elric!
アルフォンス·エルリック
You finally got down on your knees.
ようやくひざまずいたな
火打ち石を火種に
Using flint as the starter, and magnifying it with
a transmutation circle made of your own blood...
自らの血でつづった錬成陣
How can you even move with that wound?!
あの傷で　なぜ
焼いてふさいだ
I sealed it with fire!
２３度気絶しかけたがな
Although I almost fainted a few times.
貴様はこう言ったな　「まだまだ死なない」と
You said, "It'll take more than that to kill me", right?
ならば　死ぬまで殺すだけだ
Then I'll just keep killing you until you die!
Colonel!
大佐
負けたわ
I lost.
悔しいけど
It's a shame, but it doesn't feel
too bad to be killed by a man like you.
あなたみたいな男に殺られるのも悪くない
迷いのないまっすぐな目
With honest eyes with no hesitation.
楽しみね
I can't wait...
The days when those eyes will show anguish...
その目が苦悩に歪む日は
...are... close...
すぐ　そこ
大佐
Colonel!
You were all right...
無事だったのか
ご自分の心配をなさってください
Please worry about yourself!
アルフォンス
Alphonse, you have my gratitude for protecting my subordinate.
部下を守ってくれた礼を言うぞ
そんなことより　早く医者を
Forget that! We need a doctor!
That's right... Please... hurry and have a doctor see Havoc...
そうだ　早くハボックに医者を呼んでやってくれ
頼む
大丈夫　大丈夫
He'll be all right... he'll be all right...
Hey... I'm back.
えっと　ただいま
バカ　おかえり
Idiot! Welcome back!
W-Well...
い　いや　えへへっ
あっ　えっとさ　あっあの　んあっははっ　えっと
U-Umm... Where to start...
Umm...
もっ もげた
It broke off!
うわっヤバい　元に戻らない
Oh no! I can't fix this!
やれやれ　ギリギリ助かったが
Dear me, I barely managed to survive...
...but in a form like this...
このナリじゃあなぁ
誰か直してくんねぇかな
I wonder if someone can't fix me up...
Whoa! You were still alive?!
うおっ　てめぇ　まだ生きてやがったのか
お　おい　こら　何すんだ
H-Hey... stop! What are you doing?!
オレはまだ殺して殺して殺しまくってだな
I still haven't killed enough!
S... Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait! W-Wait!
ちょっ待て待て待て待て　まっ待て
やややっ　やめっ
S-S-S-Stop!
まさか
No way...
そんな
Impossible...
Hohenheim!
ホーエンハイム
Let it all out, Let it all out
I don't have to act tough, right?
強がらなくていいんだね
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
誰かが描いてった
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
壁の落書きの花が　揺れる
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
自分らしさなんて, 誰もわからないよ
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
長い長い道の途中で
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
失くしたり, 拾ったり,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
急に寂しくなって, 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
涙も　痛みも　星に変えよう
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
明日を照らす　灯りをともそう
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
小さな手かざして　ふたりで作ろう
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
星屑を　強く光る永遠を探そう
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
さよなら　いつかは来るかもしれない
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
季節はそれでも巡り巡ってく
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
小さく迷っても　歩いてく
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
君と歩いてく
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
真実は憤懣と歓喜の合わせ鏡
The truth revealed both of his emotions: joy, and unhappiness.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
捨て去った過去と対峙したとき
When the boy had to take a stand against the past he threw away,
少年は決意という名で隠していたものを暴かれる
what he had been hiding behind his resolve was exposed.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第二十話　墓前の父
Episode 20, Father Before the Grave.
涙はなくとも　泣くことはできる
It is possible to cry without tears.
人ならば
If you're a human.